<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://valentinsix.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://valentinsix.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-12-05T06:42:40+00:00</updated><id>https://valentinsix.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why Writing a Blog?</title><link href="https://valentinsix.github.io/blog/2025/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Writing a Blog?"/><published>2025-11-26T14:24:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-26T14:24:00+00:00</updated><id>https://valentinsix.github.io/blog/2025/blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://valentinsix.github.io/blog/2025/blog/"><![CDATA[<p>I thought about starting a blog a few years ago, but never found a real reason to do it. I don’t have a brand to promote, no audience to grow, and I don’t particularly enjoy writing just for the sake of it.</p> <p>So I decided to approach blogging differently. In a way, this is a space for me. I won’t spend hours polishing every post, and I’ll write to clear my thoughts and gather ideas in one place. Sure, I could keep everything private, but I might as well share it. Maybe someone will stumble upon it and find something useful.</p> <p>It’ll probably be a mess at first, but hopefully over time I’ll be able to cluster ideas together and give it some structure.</p> <p>I call this my <strong>Atomic Blog</strong>, because each post is a compilation of short and focused ideas on a specific topic. Writing this way makes the process easier, both for the writer and the reader. Also, I will probably create a post, write down some ideas, and then come back to it later if I have something to add.</p> <p>The main purposes of this blog are to:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Articulate clear ideas</strong>: Thinking can be messy, and it’s easy to lose track of good ideas or circle back to the same thoughts. I’ve realized that writing things down (especially on paper in my case) helps me develop complex ideas without constantly starting over. Writing forces you to give form to thoughts that are otherwise abstract. I see writing and thinking as two sides of the same process: to write is to think clearly enough that your ideas survive translation into words.</li> <li><strong>Centralize all ideas in one place</strong>: I often have the same ideas on multiple occasions, because I eventually forget them. This blog is a way to plant those thoughts in a small garden: hopefully I keep track of what’s growing, and I revisit it now and then.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the reasons behind starting a personal blog for clear thinking, idea organization, and knowledge sharing in academic and research contexts.]]></summary></entry></feed>